🛘 🗀 +1 (734) 496-1803 | 🔀 jwnchung@umich.edu | 🏕 jaewonchung.me | 🖸 jaywonchung | 🛅 jae-won-chung-cs

Summary .

I am a second year PhD candidate in CSE at the University of Michigan, working with Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury. My research interest is in the intersection of software systems and deep learning, with a recent focus on sustainability aspects such as energy consumption and carbon footprint. I lead the ML Energy initiative.

Education

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2021 - present

Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Mar 2015 - Aug 2021

- GPA: 4.04/4.3 (overall) 4.15/4.3 (major), Summa Cum Laude
- · Period includes two years of military service.

Publications

- Zeus: Understanding and Optimizing GPU Energy Consumption of DNN Training, Jie You*, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>*, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2023 (Acceptance rate = 18.38%)
- ShadowTutor: Distributed Partial Distillation for Mobile Video DNN Inference, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Jae-Yun Kim, Soo-Mook Moon, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP), 2020 (Acceptance rate = 28.99%)
- * Equal contribution

Experience

Energy-Efficient Systems for Machine Learning

SymbioticLab, UMich

Advisor: Mosharaf Chowdhury

Sep 2022 - Present

- Zeus: Discovered the trade-off between DNN training time and energy. Designed a Multi-Armed Bandit solution for time-energy optimization.
- Perseus (WIP): Towards Zero Energy Bloat in Large-Scale Distributed DNN Training
- Mentoring two MS students who work on expanding Zeus to various training scenarios.

Software Systems for Machine Learning

Software Platform Lab, SNU

Advisor: Byung-Gon Chun

Apr 2020 - Jun 2022

- Crane: A GPU cluster manager for AutoML workloads. Built a Kubernetes backend that scaled to 288 GPUs. Contributed core features such as automatic bootstrapping on Docker Swarm and Kubernetes and log streaming through the EFK (Elasticsearch Fluent Bit Kibana) stack.
- Participated in the writing process of Terra (NeurlPS'21), Revamper (ATC'21), and Nimble (NeurlPS'20).

Online Model Specialization for Edge Video DNN Inference

Virtual Machine and Optimization Lab, SNU

Advisor: Soo-Mook Moon

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

ShadowTutor: Knowledge distillation from the server to the edge device reduced network data transfer by 95% and increased throughput by 3x.

Few-Shot Learning with Meta-Learning

Computer Vision Lab, SNU

Advisor: Kyoung Mu Lee

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

Designed improved meta-initialization methods for Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) with neural memory modules and convex programs.

Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping with Deep Learning

Lab of Imaging Science and Technology, SNU

ADVISOR: JONGHO LEE

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

• Designed and implemented a full deep learning pipeline for QSM, a vision task for medical diagnostics with 3D MRI field data, including preprocessing (background removal, phase unwrapping, and patch slicing), augmentation (adding fake calcifications) and modeling (CAD-QSMNet).

JANUARY 8, 2023 JAE-WON CHUNG

Open Source Projects

- **BERT4Rec-VAE-Pytorch** (☆232 % 68), PyTorch implementation of BERT4Rec and Netflix VAE
- Reason (☆121 \$\mathbb{P}\$ 2), A shell for research papers
- Zeus (☆51 ₺ 7), An energy optimization framework for DNN training
- Pegasus (☆19 \$2), An SSH command runner with a focus on simplicity

Numbers as of January 5, 2023.

Honors & Awards

Nov 2022 **Carbon Hack '22 Second Best Solution**, <u>Carbon-Aware DNN Training with Zeus</u>, \$25,000

Jul 2021 **Kwanjeong Overseas Scholarship**, \$100,000 over four years

Mar 2019 **Kwanjeong Undergraduate Scholarship,** \$20,000 over two years

Green Software Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

Service

• Systems/Software Reading Group, Paper reading group inside Michigan CSE, Organizer since Fall 2022

Teaching_

- Spring 2021 Operating Systems, Main TA, Managed course projects and led group design reviews.
- Fall 2020 Computer Organization (Undergraduate architecture), Peer tutor, Provided 30 hours of online lecture, Best Tutor Award!

Skills___

Language Python, Rust, CUDA, C++, Verilog, C, Bash **Framework** PyTorch, Pandas, Matplotlib, FastAPI

Methodology Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Multi-Armed Bandit

Tool Docker, Kubernetes, KubeFlow, LaTeX

English TOEFL 120 (Perfect score), GRE 167/170/4.5

JANUARY 8, 2023 JAE-WON CHUNG 2